CAREER PROFILE

Experienced data scientist with a mathematical background. Previous experience in tutoring and small business ownership mean I am practised at explaining complex concepts and translating technical mathematics into workplace output. In short, I am a well-rounded data scientist who loves challenges and tough problems.



Data Scientist

EDUCATION

BMath in Mathematics

2013 - 2017

University of Queensland

Studied Mathematics focusing on applied areas such as statistical analysis, algorithms and optimization. Awarded the Vice Chancellor Scholarship (\$12,000 p.a.) based on academic merit.

EXPERIENCES

Data Analyst

08/2017 - 11/2017

Jacaranda Finance

Data analyst for a financial services company. During my role, I was tasked with improving their credit scoring algorithm using an internal data set. To accomplish this I implemented a variety of statistical (logistic regression, decision tree, random forest) and machine learning methods in R language and oversaw their deployment as an API.

Data Scientist Intern

08/2017 - 02/2018

Noisenet

Intern for an ambitious real estate sound monitoring start-up. In my role I wrote unit tests for an AWS Django server; scraped and managed large data sets in AWS databases; and optimized the runtime of an internal tool using

(mailto: simon@simonmcmahon.com)

**** 0490 066 236 (tel:0490 066 236)

in simon-mcmahon (https://linkedin.com/in/simonmcmahon)

simon-mcmahon (http://github.com/simonmcmahon)

PDF resume (/assets/sm_resume.pdf)

♣ Add to contacts (/assets/sm_contact.vcf)

LANGUAGES

English (Native)

INTERESTS

Hiking

Ultimate Disc

Casual Academic Tutor

mathematical improvements.

University of Queensland

Academic tutor to 25 students. Tasks involved explaining mathematical concepts, marking assignments and giving constructive feedback to students.

Private Tutor

2013 - 2018

Altius Tutoring

Founder of a 1-on-1 specialist tutoring company for Queensland senior school students. My role included tutoring, marketing, sales and client relationship management.

PROJECTS

Coding projects I have worked on in my spare time.

NY Times Sentiment Analysis (https://nytimes-emotion.herokuapp.com) - Responsive webapp analysing the emotion and bias of the NY times most shared articles by social media type. Dash by Plotly backend. Machine learning done with NLTK.

Conspiracy Trivia (https://assistant.google.com/services/a/uid/0000004af87ac8fa?hl=en) - A simple trivia game for the Google Assistant and Google Home product lines with a conspiratorial theme.

Python (numpy, pandas)		
MATLAB		
Amazon Web Services		
R language		
Database (SQlite, postgresql)		
Python (plotly, Django)		
Python (TensorFlow)		
Photoshop		